John Gibler Papers, 1890-2006
University of Minnesota Libraries
John Gibler papers
1890 2006
1950s 1990s
University of Minnesota University of Minnesota Archives [uarc]
Gibler, John W.
6 boxes
6 cubic feet
Collection contains the papers of John W. Gibler, noted breeder of cereal grains and soybeans, and alumnus of the University of Minnesota.
uarc 1180
Use of Materials
Items in this collection do not circulate and may be used in-house only.
Source of acquisition
The collection was acquired through a donation from John Gibler’s daughter, Janet Margaret Krukar in 2007.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in six series:
Professional Affiliations
Correspondence
Country Bulletins
Crop-Related Publications
Awards and Honoraria
Miscellaneous
Scope and Content
The John W. Gibler Papers include a wide range of wheat and crop breeding-related materials, including Gibler’s collection of journal articles, conference papers, plant-crossing ledgers and other technical and field-oriented materials. The materials cover the period when Gibler began his work in Mexico with Norman Borlaug in the early 1950s through the mid 1990s, when Gibler retired from consulting and international travel. The collection also includes work-related and personal correspondence. Much of the collection is in languages other than English. Because of the large volume, no attempt was made to identify the language of materials at the folder level.
The material was in no discernable order. The collection has been organized into six series: Series 1. Professional Affiliations, includes documents generated by organizations and companies Gibler worked with or for during the course of his career. Series 2. Correspondence is divided into two sub-series, Personal and Professional. Series 3. Country Bulletins, contains copies of the official publications from Central and South American organizations Gibler was affiliated with. These materials are primarily in Portuguese and Spanish. Series 4. Crop-Related Publications includes Gibler’s library of crop-related research materials. Crops featured in this section include wheat, triticale, soybeans, corn, oats and barley. The bulk of the material focuses on wheat crosses and wheat pedigrees, and includes the published crosses of wheat generated during Gibler's work in Mexico. Most materials are in English, with some in Portuguese and French. Series 5. Awards and Honorarium. Series 6. Miscellaneous, includes news clippings, photographs, and biographical information.
Biographical Sketch of John Gibler (1920-2006)
John Wesley Gibler, B.S. (1947) University of Montana; M.S. (1950), Ph.D. (1951) University of Minnesota. University of Minnesota alumnus and contemporary of Norman Borlaug. Expert in the breeding of cereal and soybeans in highly toxic soils and leader in Latin American crop development.
John Gibler was born in Willow City, South Dakota on November 10, 1920. He grew up in rural Teton County, Montana where his father and mother farmed. He served as a Navy pilot in WWII, and enrolled at the University of Montana after leaving the service, earning his bachelor's degree in 1947. Gibler then enrolled in the University of Minnesota, earning his M.S. in 1950 and Ph.D. in 1951, both in plant pathology. After receiving his doctorate, Gibler was recommended by E.C. Stakman to join Norman Borlaug in Mexico to work on wheat breeding projects. Gibler remained in Mexico through 1955. From 1955 through 1969, Gibler worked as an agricultural consultant for the Rockefeller Foundation. He provided leadership on wheat, barley and oat improvement programs in Colombia (1956-1965) and Ecuador (1965-1967). In 1968-1969, he returned to Mexico and served as Director of Agricultural Programs at CIMMYT. His twenty years in the field in South American solidified his expertise in cereal and soybean breeding and seed production in highly toxic soils.
Between 1969 and 1980, Gibler held several positions simultaneously in the public and private sector. He was Director of Massey-Ferguson International Programs based in Brazil from 1969-1980. He also served as Technical Director for FECOTRIGO (Federation of Farmer’s Wheat and Soybean Cooperatives of Rio Grand e do Sul Brazil) from 1969-1977, and Research Director for OCEPAR (Organization of Farm Cooperatives) in Brazil from 1977-1979.
Between 1955 and 1980, Gibler participated in numerous special assignments which took him around the globe. He participated in crop improvement feasibility studies in the Near East, North Africa, Turkey, Spain, and Central American countries conducted by U.S. AID, FAO, the Rockefeller and Ford Foundations, CENTO and the World Bank From 1980-1983, Gibler worked briefly for International Plant Research Institute in the Cereals Program. When that company failed, Gibler returned to consulting, and spent his remaining work years through the mid 1990s advising South and Central American agricultural ministries on crop programs, concentrating on Bolivia and Brazil.
Gibler received numerous honors for his work on wheat and triticale breeding, and was highly regarded as a program administrator. He was awarded the University of Minnesota’s E.C. Stakman award in September 2006. He Married twice; first to Catherine Marie Zander, who died in 2001, and to Bettie Rice. The Giblers had three children; Mary, Jeanette and Paul. John Gibler died December 13, 2006 in Hot Springs, AK.
Related Materials in University Archives
The John Gibler papers are one of several collections held by the University of Minnesota that document the development of agricultural practices that were central to the Green Revolution, including
Norman Borlaug papers
Elvin C. Stakman papers
John S. Niederhauser papers
Helen Hart papers
Cereal Rust Laboratory records
Department of Plant Pathology records
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of the University of Minnesota Libraries. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Gibler, John W. -- Archives.; Borlaug, N.E.; Rockefeller Foundation.; Mexico.; Brazil.; Colombia.; Green Revolution.; Wheat --Disease and pest resistance.; Wheat --Genetics.; Wheat --Mexico.
Detailed Contents
The following section contains a detailed list of the materials in the collection.
- Professional Affiliations
  - Rockefeller Foundation, Wheat, Oat and Barley program. Colombia, 1955-1965. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Wheat breeding program histories written by John Gibler, 1996. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Tibaitata, Colombia, 1955. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Includes photographs.
  - Wheat rust and wheat production in Mexico and Colombia, Gibler and Borlaug, 1952-1953. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Wheat rust, Colombia, 1962. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Wheat rust, Gibler and Borlaug, 1964-1965. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Notes on Turkish wheat rust programs, Gibler and Borlaug, 1968. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - “The Bolivian Wheat Program, Santa Cruz. A Review and Evaluation,” John Gibler, 1972. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Brazil, miscellaneous, 1972-1977. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Massey-Ferguson, 1973-1979. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Brazil seed requests to CIMMYT, 1977. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - International Plant Research Institute (IPRI), 1980s. (Box 1, Folder 35-40)
  - Dow Chemical consulting, 1986. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Kenya Agricultural Research Project consulting, 1987. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Ronco consulting, 1988-1989. (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Correspondence
  - Professional, 1950s-1990s. (Box 1, Folder 44-46)
  - Professional, 1957-1979. (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Personal, 1953, 1970s-2000. (Box 1, Folder 47-52)
    Includes correspondence with Norman Borlaug and Katherine Gibler.
  - Personal, 1958-1964. (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Country Bulletins
  - Brazil
    - “Boletim Technico” no.25, 26, 1989, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - “Controle Integrado de Doencas e de Paragas do Trigo no Rio Grande del Sul”. Centro Nacional de Pesquisa de Trigo, 1988. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - “Programa des Pesquisas,”, 1982, 1983. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Assorted wheat-related bulletins. Centro Nacional de Pesquisa de Trigo, 1984, 1986, 1987. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - “Programa de Pesquisa: resultados de pesquisa com trigo e triticale 1978-1979 and 1979-1980”. OCEPAR (Organizacao das Cooperativas do Estado do Parana), 1980, 1981. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - “Programa de Pesquita: resultados de pesquita na safra de verao, 1986-1987." OCEPAR, 1988. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - “Culturas de Inverno: resultados de pesquita, 1987-88”, Fundacao Centro de Experimentacao e Pequisa Fecotrigo (FUNDACEP Fecotrigo); "Recomendacoes da Comissao Sul Brasileira de Pesquita de Trigo-1989” (FUNDACEP Fecotrigo); Recomendacoes da Comissao Sul Brasileira de Pesquita de Trigo-1988” (FUNDACEP Fecotrigo), 1988-1989. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - OCEPAR "Programa de Pesquisa,", 1980. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - OCEPAR Wheat crosses, 1981. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - OCEPAR Correspondence, 1984. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - OCEPAR "Informe Tecnico,", 1984. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - OCEPAR. “Resultados Dos Ensaios Sul Brasileiros de Trigo” XXII Reunio Da Comissao Sul-Brasileira De Pesquisa De Trigo Passo Fundo, Brasil, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bolivia
    - “Boletin OAP-5”; “Boletin OAP-9”, 1988-1989. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - “Policy Alternatives for Wheat Production and Marketing of Wheat in Bolivia” Report 110, Food and Grain Institute, Manhattan, KS, December 1988. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "Wheat growing plan for Chuquisaca, 1990-1991. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1988-1989. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Uruguay. “Archivo Fitotecnico del Uruguay”, volume 5, Montivedeo, 1953. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - United States
    - USDA. “Classification of American Wheat Varieties”. Bulletin No. 1074, 1922. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous wheat-related bulletins from the USDA, 1890-1930. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - USDA and Agricultural Research Services, 1950s. (Box 2, Folder 14)
      “Reaction of Selected Wheats to Six Races of Stem Rust in Puerto Rico and St. Croix, VI, in 1954-1955” T. Theis and H.A. Rodenheiser, undated. “Reaction of Individual Races of Stem and Leaf Rust of Selected Wheat Varieties in 1953” Bayles, B.B., compiler, 1953. “Report of Uniform Eastern Soft Winter Wheat Nurseries for 1953” Bayles, B.B., 1953. Supplement to the report “Reaction to Individual races of Stem and Leaf Rust of Selected Varieties in 1953”, compiled by B.B. Bayles, March, 1954, No. 302CC”, 1953. “Data on Wheat Breeding Materials Resistant to Stem Rust Race 15B in the greenhouse at Beltsville, MD., in 1950-1951 and their field reaction in the summer of 1951” B.B. Bayles, compiler, April, 1951.
    - USDA and Agricultural Research Services, 1950s. (Box 2, Folder 15)
      “Reactions of Wheat from the World Collections to 8 Races of Stem Rust in the Seedling and Adult Stages at 65-70 degrees and 80-85 degrees F. and 80-85 F. in the greenhouse at Beltsville, MD., 1951-1952”: Lowther, C.V. 1951. “Wheats From World Collections Resistant to Rust” Bayles, B.B., Ward, JJ, Borlaug, N.E., 1952. “Disease and Agronomic Data on the Foreign Spring Wheats (P.I. Nos. 170838- 178098, Inclusive) For the World Collection In 1951”. Ward, D.J. compiler, 1953. “Summary Report of the Reaction of Wheat and Oats to Cereal Rusts in Argentina, Brazil, Chile, and Peru in 1951-1952”. H.A. Rodenheiser and C.S. Holton. 1952.
    - USDA “Research Bulletin 281,”, October 1977. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - USDA “Research Bulletin 285,”, July 1978. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - USDA “Research Bulletin 296,”, July 1981. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - USDA “Research Bulletin 297,”, October 1981. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - UDSA "Memo on wheat variety descriptions for wheat workers,", 1972. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - USDA “Distribution of the Varieties and Classes of Wheat in the U.S., 1979” Statistical Bulletin no. 676, 1980. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - USDA “Classification of Wheat Varieties Grown in the United States.” J.Allen Clarke and B.B. Bayles. Technical Bulletin no. 459, April 1935. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - USDA “Classification of Wheat Varieties grown in the United States in 1939” Technical Bulletin no. 795, June 1942. (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Folder includes index cards with wheat breed names and notations.
    - USDA “Classification of Wheat Varieties Grown in the United States in 1949” Technical Bulletin no. 1083, March 1954. (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Crop-Related Publications
  - “Wheats From J.W. Taylor Beltsville Breeding Program Grown At Several Stations in 1952.” B.B. Bayles, compiler, January 1953. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Grids with data pertaining to wheat grown with rust at Chapingo, Mexico and “Disease reaction of Mexican Wheats in the Field,” Forest Products Pathology Nursery, Madison, Wisconsin, 1952. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - National Wheat Research Conference program, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - “Registration of Improved Wheat Varieties XX”; “Registration of Improved Wheat Varieties, XXI”, “Registration of Improved Wheat Varieties XXII”, Registration of Improved Wheat Varieties XXIII”, “Registration of Improved Wheat Varieties XXIV”, Registration of Wheat Varieties, XVIII” in Agronomy Journal. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - “Wheat In New York” Reisner, J.A. Masters Thesis, Cornell University, 1915. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Wheat Newsletter. Vols. VI, VIII, IX, X; Kansas State University and University of Saskatchewan, 1959, 1961-1963. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Annual Wheat Newsletter. Vols XXVII, XXIV, XXIII: Kansas State University and the Canada Department of Agriculture, 1977-1978, 1980. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Origini, Suviluppi, Lavori e Risultati. Istituto Nazionale di Genetica per la Cerealicoltura in Roma, 1932. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Annali dell’Istituto sperimentale per la Cerealicoltura. Rome. Vol X, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Assorted wheat-related reprints from Kansas Agricultural Experiment Station, USDA, Canadian Department of Agriculture, Agronomia Lusitana (Portugal), Phytopathology; Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, and Journal of Agricultural Research, 1931-1949. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Assorted wheat-related reprints from USDA, FAO, Agricultural Experiment Station University of Minnesota, Pacific Cooperative Extension Stations, 1950-1960. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Assorted wheat-related reprints from FAO, Institute of Plant Breeding, Crop Science, Wheat Information Service Kyoto Japan, Commonwealth Scientific and Industrial Research Organization, 1961-1969. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Assorted wheat-related reprints from Ohio Agricultural Research and Development Center, USDA, Euphytica, Department of Agronomy and range Science University of California at Davis, CIMMYT, 1970-1979. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Assorted wheat-related reprints from the Noble Foundation, Crop Development center, University of Saskatchewan, Theoretical and Applied Genetics, 1980-1985. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Assorted wheat-related publications, undated, 1930s-1970s. (Box 3, Folder 6-8)
  - “Production and Performance of Common and Durum Wheats and Triticale at the University of California Imperial Valley Field Station, El Centro, in 1981, 1982, and 1983” and “Production and Performance of Common and Durum Wheats and Triticale at the University of California Imperial Valley Field Station, El Centro California for 1980, 1981 and 1982” in Agronomy Progress Report, 1982, 1983. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO) reprints, 1960-1965, 1975. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Wheat, Australia, undated. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Wheat in Great Britain. John Percival, 1934. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Wheat in India: its production, varieties and improvement. Albert Howard; Imperial Department of Agriculture in India, 1909. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Wheat in India; Unidentified published manuscript, undated. (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
  - Annual Wheat Newsletter. Vol. XXIII Kansas State University and Canada Department of Agriculture, May 1977. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Wheat plantings in Jordan and Saudi Arabia with additional materials on wheat varietals form the USDA, undated. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Kenya Wheat Program, undated. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - “Wheat Varieties in South Africa: their history and development until 1912” J.H. Neethling. Stellenn-Elsenburg College of Agriculture at the University of Stellenbosch, 1932. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - “Wheat Production in South Africa”, Dr. J.T.R. Sim; Bulletin N. 334 (Stellenbosch-Elsenburg Farmers Series No. 226) Department of Agriculture, 1953. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - “Report of the Wheat Stem Rust Conference,” University of Minnesota, 1950. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - “Report of the Yellow Rust Trials Project in 1962”, Ir. E. Ubels and Eva Fuchs; Institute for Phytopathological Research, Holland and Biologisch Bundesanstalt fur Land- und Forstwirschaft, Braunschweig, Germany, 1964. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - “Stem Rust of Wheat, Barley and Rye in Canada in 1977”, G.J Green: Inventaire des maladies des plantes su Canada, 58:3, 1978. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - “Development of Salt-Tolerant Wheat: a preliminary business prospectus,” Ralph W. Kingsbury, July 1985. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Unpublished paper.
  - Unpublished preliminary reports on reactions of wheat to stem, leaf and stripe rust and mildew. USDA/ARS Field Crop Research branch, 1951-1953. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Unpublished preliminary reports on reactions of winter wheat to the introduction of rust varieties in wheat rust nurseries, 1958-1961, 1963-1964, 1966. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Unpublished preliminary reports on reactions of spring wheat to the introduction of rust varieties in wheat rust nurseries. USDA/ARS Crops Research Division, 1954-1963. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Unpublished preliminary reports of reactions in wheat to stripe rust and other disease-producing organisms, 1960, 1966. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Assorted issues of unpublished reports relating to wheat breeding and rusts in facilities in the United States and Mexico, 1952-1953, 1960. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    Several reports co-authored by N.E. Borlaug.
  - Unpublished preliminary reports on reactions in wheat to stem, leaf and stripe rust and other diseases, 1971-1975. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous government reports on agricultural production and wheat taxonomies, undated, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Assorted periodical articles and reports on wheat, 1978-1988. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - “Observaciones Sobre Variedades Y Especies de Trigo,” Instituto de Fitotecnia, 1954. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - “Tres anos de ensayos con variedades de trigo en el Paraguay” Ministerio de Agricultura Y Ganaderia, Paraguay, 1970. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - “Registered Field Crop Varieties: 1926-1981,” Crop Science Society of America, Madison, WI, 1982. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - De Santa a Pescadora: A saga da soja pelso campos do Rio Grande. Luiz Pedro Bonett. Cruz Alta, Brazil, 1987. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Journal article and list of hybrids of Triticum, Aegilops, Secale and Agropyron, undated. (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - “Uptake of nutrients by plant roots.” From barley research in Norway, 1986. (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - “Chemical Castration in Rice,” anonymous unpublished paper, undated. (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - "Registrations of Crop Varietals," In Crop Sciences, vol 21, November-December 1981. (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - “Corn Genes and Big Dollars” in Technology Review, November-December 1981. (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Compendium of Corn Diseases and Compendium of Soybean Diseases, American Phytopathological Society, 1980, 1982. (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Manual papra el control de las plagas en el cultivo de la soya. ANAPO-CIAT, undated. (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Referred publications of J.B. Thomas. Focus on chromosome pairing, 1971-1979. (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Regional Wheat Workshop, Ford Foundation, Beirut, Lebanon, 1972. (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - “Consolidated List of Abbreviations of Wheat and Barley Varieties,” compiled at regional wheat workshop, Beirut, Lebanon. ALAD-Ford Foundation, 1982, 1983. (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Third Regional Wheat Workshop, sponsored by FAO, Ford and Rockefeller Foundations and CIMMYT, Tunis, Tunisia, April-May 1975. (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Assorted wheat crossing publications, including glossary, identification schemes, handwritten notes, undated. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - “Australian Wheat Varieties; supplement No. 1”. Ferns, Fitzsimmons, Martin, et al., undated. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - “Lista de Progenitores Resistentes a Puccina Glumarum: Empleados en la formacion de los comuestos (Sintetico) Colombia, undated. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - “Pedigrees of various Winter and Spring Wheat varieties,” Rockefeller Foundation, undated. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - “Sistemica de Trigos” I & III and “Novos Trigos Portugueses: classificacao e descricao botanica,", undated. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Wheat crosses. Typescript. Carbons of original.110 pages, undated. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Wheat cultivars. Handwritten notes identifying origins of names of wheat varieties,“, undated. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Yugoslavia” is prominent on the first page. Included in the folder are two brochures in Turkish and English with descriptions of durum and bread wheat cultivars from the Mediterranean region.
  - Untitled publication in French with wheat variety names, circa 1974. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - “Wheat pedigrees and breeding systems,”, undated. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Unattributed, unpublished paper concerning systems of designation crosses and hybrids used by the breeding programs of the Rockefeller Foundation.
  - “Tipos de Infeccion producidos por Puccinia Graminis triticci sobre lineas puras des trigo en estado de plantulas…’’ at Tibaitata (I) y Villa de Leiva (II). Typescript list, 1950. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - “Tipos de Infeccion produccio por Puccinia glumarum triticina, y P. Graminis gritici sobre variedades de trigo bajo codiciones de inverndero. La Picota, Mexico, 1950. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Wheat crossing publications and lists relating to Kenya wheat production, 1952-1959. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Pedigree de las Cruzas Interspecificas de Trigo, 1953. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Wheat crosses, Mexico, 1953. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Unbound boards, typescript and handwritten with wheat crosses. Title on inside page is “Expert. XIII: Fi de cruces hechas en Picota 1950” with notation in green pencil next to title “Lineas para NEB” Annotation all in Spanish. Approximately 200 pages.
  - “Historia Cruzas 1-3342 Mexico, March-April 1945. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Handwritten title appears on front board. Header on first page of list as follows: "Historia de las cruzas hechas por el personal de la Oficina de Estudios Especiale Historia de cruzas hechas Chapingo." Approximatel 135 pages.
  - Inventory, 1951-1952. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    2 Dup (title) on front board. Introducciones +. Fundacion Rockefeller appears on title page. On first page of the history, header reads “Lineas de Trigo de la Oficina de Investigaciones Especiales de Colombia”.
  - Inventory, 1958. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    No front board. No interior titles. Typescript of wheat crosses. After page 70, title page reads “(Copia) 1. Tibaitaba,
  - Wheat pedigrees and crosses, Colombia, 1958. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Including paper titled “Inheritance of resistance to Stripe Rust, Puccinia Glumarum in Bonza and other wheat varieties” Maual Rosero and John Gibler. Report. IV Reunion Latinamericano de Filotecina, Santiago Chile.
  - Notes on wheat crosses, worldwide, undated, 1963. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - “Descripcion de las Varidados de trigo Cultivades en la Argentina. Rath, Conta, Tombetta, et al, Collecion Agropopecuaria del I.N.T.A, Buenos Aires, 1964. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Wheat Crosses, Mexico, 1967. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Recently named lines and varieties of bread wheat, durum, barley and triticale, 1974. (Box 4, Folder 22)